Hey, there.
嗨 大家好
Let's talk about the shell The shell
我们来聊聊 shell 它是
is a command-line interface for running programs
在计算机上运行程序的
on your computer.
命令行界面
You type commands at a prompt.
你在命令提示符下键入命令
And the shell runs programs for you and shows you their output.
shell 会为你运行程序 并显示输出
Developers use it a lot, because it's fast and flexible.
开发人员经常使用它 因为它快速灵活
Also, the vast majority of web servers in the wild
此外 绝大多数 Web 服务器
run on Linux.
都在 Linux 上运行
And the shell is a vital tool for deployment
而 shell 是在 Linux 服务器上进行部署
and remote administration on Linux servers.
和远程管理的重要工具
Now, compared to using a graphical environment, or GUI,
但是 相比于使用图形环境或 GUI
when you use the shell, you do have
在使用 shell 时 你确实需要
to remember a bunch of magic words and incantations.
记住一堆魔幻的词和咒语
But in exchange, once you get some practice in,
但是作为回报 一旦你有了实践经验
you get to do things really quickly
就能非常快速地执行命令
without a lot of pointing and clicking.
而无需进行各种指点和点击
It's kind of like programming, really.
这跟编程很像
If you've used the JavaScript console in your browser,
如果你在浏览器中用过 JavaScript 控制台
or any other programming languages interpreter, well,
或任何其他编程语言解释器
the idea of the shell's command line is pretty much the same.
会发现 shell 命令行的原理几乎是一样的
You type out instructions in a special language,
你使用专门语言输入指令
and the system runs them.
系统运行它们
And it shows you the output underneath.
然后在下面显示输出
Then you get another prompt.
然后你会得到另一个提示符
And you can do it again.
你再重复相同的操作
The JavaScript console is a command line for your browser.
JavaScript 控制台是用于浏览器的命令行
But the shell is a command line for your computer in general,
而 shell 是广泛用于计算机的命令行
working with files and directories,
使用文件和目录
running programs, and interacting
运行程序 并与其他计算机
with other computers.
进行交互
Now, the program that we use to interact with the shell
我们用于与 shell 交互的程序
is called a terminal program.
称为终端程序
If you're on Mac or Linux, you've already
如果你使用的是 Mac 或 Linux 那么你已经
got a good one of these.
有一个很好的终端程序了
It's got an icon that looks like this.
它有一个这样的图标
If you're on Windows, though, we'll
如果你用的是 Windows 我们来
take a look at how to install a shell and terminal
看看如何安装与 Mac 和 Linux 上
program that works the same as the ones on Mac and Linux.
具有相同作用的 shell 和终端程序
Windows does have a built-in command shell.
Windows 有一个内置的命令 shell
It's based on the old MS-DOS command line rather than
它基于旧的 MS-DOS 命令行 而非
the UNIX heritage.
UNIX 遗产
For web developers, a UNIX-style shell
对于 Web 开发者来说 UNIX 风格的 shell
is pretty much a professional standard,
差不多是专业标准的
because so much of the web runs on Linux servers.
因为很多 Web 在 Linux 服务器上运行
So that's what we'll be looking at in this course.
这就是我们这节课要看的
Specifically, will be using the Bash shell,
具体来说 我们将使用 Bash shell
which is by far the most popular UNIX-style shell.
这是迄今为止使用最多的 UNIX 风格的 shell
The first thing we'll do in this course is to get you up
在这节课中 我们要做的第一件事是
and running in the terminal.
让你在终端上开始运行
Then we'll take a quick tour of show commands
然后我们将快速演练用于
for navigating files and directories.
导航文件与目录的 show 命令
You'll learn commands for downloading files from the web,
你将学习从 Web 下载文件、
viewing text files, and customizing the shell itself
查看文本文件和自定义 shell 本身
to make it friendlier.
来提高友好体验的命令
So let's get started.
那么我们开始吧